# GERMAN VICENTE GONZALEZ

5561 NW 112 Ave, Apt 103, Doral, FL 33178. USA. Cel: (786) 499 0271. german.gonzalez@estrategonline.com Linkedin Profile

## **SUMMARY**

Bilingual Human Resources/Labor Relations & Project Manager with extensive experience in the professional services, construction and oil industries. Expert in leading a variety of projects from formulation and planning to execution. Skilled at strategic planning, process management, negotiations, administration, general services and all HR and labor relations processes. Coach and Trainer. Versatile, flexible and with a clear entrepreneurial mindset.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# Go2Go Trading Corp, Miami, USA

2018 - present

Vicepresident

Managing the USA operations to introduce the Grand Tepui Soapery Brand from idea to market.

## AddtoCart Brands Corp, Miami, USA

2018 - present

Owner & General Manager

Under this company I have started several e-commerce initiatives through different marketplaces like Amazon FBA, eBay, Etsy, Jet, Bonanza, managing the supply and marketing processes and all administrative activities, including outsourced processes and suppliers research, product selection, purchasing and shipping to market.

#### Consorcio PPE Pro Planta, Puerto Ordaz, Venezuela

2013 - 2018

Pulpaca Project – US\$900MM Pulp and Paper Processing Plant Construction Project Project Manager of Human Resources and Labor Relations (contract based)

Defined all processes related to human resources and labor, workforce, government, union and community relations. Led the recruitment, direct and indirect compensation, training, payroll and claims administration processes for the 1.000 company employees. Directed the labor relations for three different companies involved in the project. Managed all issues concerning unions, HR & LR organizational processes, labor safety committees, employee safety and security, industrial protection, government and relations with the nearby communities.

- Led the human resources and labor relations management of a workforce of 1,000 employees for a pulp and paper processing plant construction project, directing policies and procedures for 3 companies during 3 years.
- Managed two massive layoff processes involving 1.800 employees without major incidents, working with management, unions, communities and government officials to avoid public and internal disruptions.
- Negotiated and solved all labor issues with 2 Anzoátegui state construction unions, well known by its aggressive approach towards company officials, maintaining good working relations while being named exclusive spokesman for all construction, health & industrial safety, industrial protection, general services, personnel transportation, community relations and other company
- Reduced to zero the general labor stoppages during the last 12 months of the project.

BPO, HR/Labor Relations, Management Consulting, Negotiations, Training and E-learning. President

Owned and led the firm including managing operations, marketing and sales of services. Managed all the firm projects and provided direct attention to customers. Headcount: 17

- Created a client portfolio that included multinational oil companies, bank, services and construction including Total, Gazprom, Baker Hughes, Weatherford, Dresser Rand, Geoservices, DHL, Bandes, Bancoex, Fluor, Cemex, Skanska, and Inelectra.
- Increased the firm's sales 30% each year during the first 5 years.
- Managed all distribution and warehouse operations personnel for DHL in Venezuela, during 2 years, with a headcount of 100 employees.
- Outsourced several consulting HR projects for multinational companies in topics such as: strategic planning, processes management, labor relations, training and development, competencies, etc.
- Developed, during 6 consecutive years, new business opportunities for the firm expanding BPO services to security, safety, maintenance, warehouse management, plant operations and construction.
- Conceived, designed, developed and implemented an online training solution called <a href="https://www.tucursoenlinea.com">www.tucursoenlinea.com</a> which offers online training courses in Spanish for the Latam corporate community.
- Developed over several training programs offered to customers including topics like leadership development, teamwork, problem analysis and decision making, internal customer relations, strategic collective bargaining, labor negotiations, etc.
- Received an average of 95% positive feedback from clients in the design and delivery of services.
- Hired and trained a total of 1500 employees for the company and clients during 6 years.

#### Grupo Alvica SCS (JV Fluor/Inelectra), Barcelona, Venezuela

2002 - 2004

Hamaca Project – US\$ 1,200MM oil upgrader plant construction project for PDVSA/Chevron/Conoco. Project Manager of Industrial Relations (contract based)

Defined all processes related to industrial, workforce, government, union and community relations. Directed the labor relations for 50 different companies involved in the project, leading the team of LR managers. Managed all issues concerning to contractor's employees, unions, LR organizational processes, industrial safety, employee security, government and relations with the nearby communities.

- Led the labor relations management of a workforce of 15,000 employees for an oil upgrader plant construction project, directing policies and procedures for up to 50 companies during 3 years.
- Permanently solved a union crisis that had to be resolved with the intervention of the country's president after 2 weeks of conflicts.
- Supported, together with the rest of project management team, the resolution of an international arbitration procedure which allowed the company to gain US\$ 200MM.
- Reduced to zero the general labor stoppages during the last 15 months of the project.
- Assured a percentage of jobs for the unemployed of the surrounding communities as part of the company's social responsibility efforts.
- Solved all employee, union and community issues/crisis as they emerged.
- Won the Project Performance Excellence Award for 2002.

# Personnel Support, S.A., Caracas, Venezuela

1999 - 2002

Outsourcing and Consulting services provider for major oil companies.

**Business Development Director** 

• Provided professional services to ExxonMobil, Total, Enron, among others, in personnel recruiting, labor relations, contractor's management, security, general services and maintenance.

- Created a client portfolio of 6 multinational clients in three years managing projects related to recruiting and labor relations consulting.
- Doubled the sales yearly, reaching a total of US\$ 5 MM during the last year.
- Participated as Negotiator in the first collective bargaining agreements of the private oil companies.
- Managed the labor relations outsourcing contracts awarded in the Cerro Negro, Sincor and Accroven projects for a total of 20.000 construction workers

#### Petroleos de Venezuela, Venezuela

1982 - 1999

*Venezuela's National Oil Company – Production of 3MM bl/day and sales of 100 billion dollars/yr* Spent 17 years in PDVSA and its associated companies. Last positions held were:

Human Resources Manager for Petrolera Ameriven, S.A. (1998 - 1999)

Project Member/Negotiator for Oil Industry Collective Bargaining Agreement (1997)

- Led a team of 20 experts including advisors in labor costs, fringe benefits, compensation, operations, and labor relations.
- Designed and presented all the negotiation strategies to the negotiation team for approval.

Contractors Administration Manager - West E&P Division (1996 - 1997)

- Saved US\$ 40 MM to the company by reviewing and adapting the work processes and creating a system that better controlled fringe benefits for contractor's employees.
- Reduced in half the number of registered workers to 15,000 by auditing in situ the contractor's operations.
- Modernized the contractor's administration and control system to support business processes and include a complete registry of the contractor's employee information.
- Successfully integrated and aligned the function to all other interrelated business processes (finance, contract originators) changing the perceived value the company had about the department.

Various HR and labor relations positions at different levels (1982 - 1996)

#### **EDUCATION**

**Master of Science (Ms) Information Technology**, Instituto Tecnologico de Estudios Superiores de Monterey, Mexico, Specialization: IT Services Management | GPA: 95/100

**Master in Business Administration (MBA)**, Indiana University, South Bend, Indiana, USA, Major: International Business Management | GPA: 3.71/4.00

**Bachelor in Business Administration,** Universidad Nacional Experimental Simón Rodríguez, Caracas, Venezuela, Major: Organization and Systems | GPA: 4.6/5.00

#### RELEVANT TRAINING

- Harvard Negotiation Workshop. Cambridge Consultants. April 2004
- Project Management Program. IESA. July 2003
- Service Companies Strategic Management Program. IESA. October 2000
- Outsourcing Global Summit. Orlando, FL. February 2000
- World Congress on Human Resources Management "HR Global 98". July 1998
- Financial Management Program. IESA. May 1998
- Strategic Collective Bargaining. U. of Michigan. Ann Arbor, MI. August 1993